Hello, and welcome to week five of our image and video processing class.
大家好 欢迎来到图像和视频处理课程的第五周
This is a very fun and exciting week for a number of reasons.
很多原因使这周的课变得非常有趣和激动人心
First of all, image and video segmentation is a fun topic as we're
首先 图像和视频分割是一个有意思的主题
going to see in the videos during this week.
我们将在这周的视频中发现这一点
Second, because during this week we're going to be transitioning from the
其次 这周我们将从基础的内容
fundamental material to the more advanced material.
逐渐过渡到更为高级的内容
The fundamental material is as we talk, that material that is used every day and
我们所学过的基础内容就是 那些每天都会被使用到的知识
you can not take a class in image processing without knowing it.
并且所有的图像处理课程里都会涉及到它
The more advanced material is material that has been deviled up in the recent
而更高级的内容则是 那些在近些年才被发展和研究的技术
years and is also extremely useful. And as we are going to see, it actually
并且也是极其有用的技术 在接下来我们将看到
often forms parts of very important products today in industry for image and
这类技术通常是 当今图像和视频处理行业中
video processing. So let's just get into image
至关重要产品的组成部分 下面就让我们来学习图像分割技术
segmentation. As I say,
就像我所说的
it's going to be a lot of fun. But what is image segmentation?
这将会非常有趣 那么什么是图像分割呢？
We should basically first of all try to answer that question.
首先 我们将试着来回答这个问题
And we are going to answer that question with a few examples.
用一些例子来回答这个问题
In image segmentation the basic idea is that we want to separate objects.
图像分割的基本原理是 我们想要将物体分离出来
We want to call different objects by different names, depending on some
依据对象的一些属性 给不同对象不同的命名
properties of those objects. So for example, here we have a cat and we
比如说 这里有一只猫
want to make sure that we find the boundary of this cat and we can separate
我们想要确保能找到它的边界
the cat here from it's background. So here, we have to cut and here we have
从而能将猫从背景中分离出来 所以 我们得到了这只猫
the background. So we manage to separate objects in the
然后得到这个背景 这样我们就成功地分离出了图像中的对象
image. Sometimes the user is going to help us to
有时候 用户可以帮助我们来进行分割
do that. For example, the user can mark this is my
比如 用户可以标记这个为图像的前景
foreground. This is what I care, the objects I care.
也就是想要获得的对象
This is the background. The objects I don't care.
而标记这是背景 也就是我们不关心的对象
Just two very simple marks and from that, we basically need to develop a technique
只是利用两个非常简单的标记 就可以开发出一种技术
that will basically extract the horses from the background.
将马匹从背景中提取出来
And sometimes, this type of segmentation is called foreground background
有些时候 这类分割被称为前景背景分离
separation. Once we do that, we can, for example
对图像做了分割之后 我们可以进行
change the background. Something that is done very, very often
改变背景等操作 这些操作被广泛和频繁地使用于电影工业中
in the movie industry. Changing background of different scenes,
改变不同场景的背景
as we are going to see in a second. So this is kind of foreground background
一会儿我们就将看到 这就是前景背景分离
separation. Sometimes, what we actually need is to
有时候 我们真正需要的
label every thing that have been seen the image.
是标记出图像中所有能看到的事物
So to find regions in these image, which is an image of neurons taking with a
在最后一周的课程中 我们将会涉及到电子显微镜技术
technique called electro microscopy that we are going to discuss later in this, in
利用这种技术 我们拍摄了这幅神经元的图像 为了划定图像中的区域
the last week of this class. We have a, as I say, images of neurons
对于这幅微电子显微技术拍摄的神经元图像
from electron microscopy and the idea is that we want to label every pixel,
我们想要依据像素所属的分类
according to the class that, that pixel belongs to.
来标记每一个像素
So basically we are coloring the image. We are saying all this region should have
我们给图像着色 这个区域的所有像素都应该有相同的标记
the same label. It belongs to the same class,
因为 它们属于相同的分类
the same type of object, the same type of tissue.
相同类别的对象目标 相同类别的细胞组织
So we are not subtracting photograph fr, from background.
这并非是从背景中提取图像
We're basically labeling every single region of the image and we get all these
而是标记出图像中的每一个区域 得到所有的区域
segments, and then we can do analysis. Finally, we also have the same problems
从而可以对之进行分析 最后 对于视频来说
in video and we see that here. And this is a video that we have already
这些原理也是一样的 请看这里 这是在课程的一开始
saw at the very beginning of the class, they just basically run it.
大家就看过的一个视频 我来播放一下
We have the video and we have a similar video, but with a different background.
这是这个视频 另外这个与之类似 但是背景不同
For doing that, we had to extract the main object here from the video.
为了做到这样 我们需要将视频中这个主要的对象提取出来
So, we are able to produce a different background for that.
从而能为它制作出一个不同的背景
And basically, this is what's behind a very important component of one of
这就是隐含在 Adobe 公司的产品 After Effects 背后
Adobe's products, called After Effects. And we are going to learn that.
关键的组成部分 在后面的视频中 我们将会学习到它的原理
We are going to learn exactly what's the underlying technology for basically the
我们将会学习到 After Effects 中的视频分割
video segmentation in After Effects. So,
和这一技术背后的原理
there are just some examples. Now, what we have to do is learn how we
以上都是一些例子 而我们需要学习的是
solve all of these very interesting image and video segmentation problems.
如何解决这些问题 这些非常有趣的图像和视频分割问题
And we're going to do that exactly, starting in the next video.
在下一个视频中 我们将真正开始学习这些内容
See you then, thank you.
到时候再见 谢谢大家 //果壳教育无边界字幕组 | 林小七Lynn |  风过成伤 | luoyetx